VINAY SHARMA

A-468 New Ashok Nagar, Delhi, DL 110096 • 959 936 3682 • foxgallivanter@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Expert Process Trainer successful at demonstrating technical expertise and taking ownership of training modules that benefit the entire team. Confident and adaptable instructor with a strong work ethic and dedication to business success.

Skills

- Training program development
- Subject matter expertise
- Instructional strategies
- Customer/Client relations

- Resource Planning
- Excel in presentation Skills
- Excellent communication skills
- Good command on excel

Work History

Product and Process Trainer, 01/2017 to Current **Hinduja Global Solutions Limited** – Noida, UP

- Created unique materials to support training programs.
- Delivered robust training courses via variety of methods, including classroom and e-learning programs.
- Developed new and improved training programs to fit undeserved areas.
- Managed escalated customer orders in timely and professional manner.
- Facilitated coach the coach to the supervisors.
- Identify training need and do analysis, Also conduct refreshers.
- Deals with client to understand business requirement and execute the action plan.
- Monitor system and resource utilization effectively.
- 5 times Best trainer award basis on best throughput and delivery content.
- Certified trainer through Airtel foundation program by Airtel.
- Also participated in TTT (Train the Trainer) workshop.
- Observed individual behaviors and suspect actions, and reported issues to supervisory staff.
- Facilitated group sessions and provided one-on-one support.

Advisor, 01/2017 to 04/2018

Hinduja Global Solutions Limited - Noida, UP

- Resolve customer issues for their bill dispute and network related queries.
- Suggest customer best suitable plan as per their usage.
- Handle escalation calls and do follow-up for such cases.

Technical Support, 12/2014 to 02/2016

I Energizer – Noida, UP

- Technical support to high end Samsung phone user for their issues.
- Take remote for the issues which were not resolved over call.
- Engaged end users and answered questions via email, phone, and website live chat and in forums.
- Followed up with clients to ensure optimal customer satisfaction following support engagement and problem resolution.

Education

B.Tech: Electronics and Communications Engineering, 2014 **Pranveer Singh Institute Of Technology, Kanpur** - Kanpur, UP

Accomplishments

- *Interactive Learning*Introduced and encouraged debate-style classroom setting to increase student active participation and critical thinking.
- Administration
 Managed coach the coach program that resulted in positive feedback and coaching of the employees to achieve the goals.
- Organized contest based learning atmosphere to add fun in learning.
- Awarded as Best Trainer 5 times in two quarter.

Certifications

Certified trainer from airtel through "Airtel Foundation Program" Participated in Train the Trainer workshop.

Personal Details

<u>Personal Details:-</u> Name: Vinay Sharma

Gender: Male

Father's Name: Siya Nath Sharma

Nationality: Indian DOB: 08-Dec-1993

Location: A-468 New Ashok Nagar New Delhi=110096

Language: Hindi, English

Date: